{
    "questions": [
        {
            "Question": "The last Nanda ruler of Magadha who was overthrown by Chandragupta Maurya with the help of Chanakya was",
            "optionA": "  Mahapadmananda ",
            "optionB": "  Dhanananda ",
            "optionC": "  Navananda ",
            "optionD": "  Not known ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSakatala found Chanakya to take his revenge from Dhana Nanda by ending his rule. Shaktar (395\u2013319 BC) was the Prime minister of Dhana Nanda - the last king of the Nanda Dynasty, which originated from the region of Magadha in ancient India during the 5th and 4th centuries BC. ",
            "keyString": "695622s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which dynasty immediately succeeded the Maurya dynasty and ruled Magadha Kingdom?",
            "optionA": "  Satavahana ",
            "optionB": "  Sunga ",
            "optionC": "  Nanda ",
            "optionD": "  Kanva ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAfter the Mauryan rule Pushyamitra, the founder of the Sungadynasty established his rule. The Sungas ruled for over a hundred years. The extent of the Sunga kingdom under Pushyamitra extended from Punjab and extended to the southern regions of the Narmada. The Sunga dynasty had a line of ten rulers. The last of the Sunga king was Devabhuti. ",
            "keyString": "738496s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The 'Ajivikas' were",
            "optionA": "  Sect contemporary to the Buddha ",
            "optionB": "  Breakaway branch of the Buddhists ",
            "optionC": "  Sect founded by Charvaka ",
            "optionD": "  Sect founded by Shankaracharya ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAjivika (IAST: Ajivika) is one of the nastika or \"heterodox\" schools of Indian philosophy. Purportedly founded in the 5th century BCE by Makkhali Gosala, it was a \u015brama\u1e47a movement and a major rival of vedic religion, early Buddhism and Jainism. ",
            "keyString": "738532s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Whose army did Alexander the Greek ruler confront on the banks of the river Jhelum?",
            "optionA": "  Chandragupta Maurya ",
            "optionB": "  Ambi ",
            "optionC": "  Ohanananda ",
            "optionD": "  Porus ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Battle of the Hydaspes was fought in 326 BC between Alexander the Great and King Porus of the Paurava kingdom on the banks of the river Jhelum (known to the Greeks as Hydaspes) in the Punjab region of the Indian subcontinent (modern-day Punjab, Pakistan). ",
            "keyString": "738550s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Name of Republic which was a confederacy to tribes in the 6th century B.C",
            "optionA": "  Gandhara ",
            "optionB": "  Vajji ",
            "optionC": "  Koushal ",
            "optionD": "  Avanti ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tVajji (Sanskrit: Vrji) or Vrijji was a confederacy of neighbouring clans including the Licchavis and one of the principal mah\u0101janapadas of Ancient India. The area they ruled constitutes the region of Mithila in northern Bihar and their capital was the city of Vaishali. ",
            "keyString": "738565s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "During Kanishka's reign, the centre of political activity shifted from Magadha to",
            "optionA": "  Delhi ",
            "optionB": "  Ayodhya ",
            "optionC": "  Kannauj ",
            "optionD": "  Purushapura (Peshawar) ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDuring Kanishka's reign, the centre of political activity shifted from Magadha to Purushapura (Peshawar). ",
            "keyString": "738581s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which area of India was known as Avantika in ancient times?",
            "optionA": "  Avadh ",
            "optionB": "  Ruhelkhand ",
            "optionC": "  Bundelkhand ",
            "optionD": "  Malwa ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn ancient city situated on the eastern bank of the Kshipra River, Ujjain was the most prominent city on the Malwa plateau of central India for much of its history. It emerged as the political centre of central India around 600 BCE.",
            "keyString": "779634s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Name the kingdom which first used elephants in wars",
            "optionA": "  Kosala ",
            "optionB": "  Magadha ",
            "optionC": "  Champa ",
            "optionD": "  Avanti ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIf we read the ancient indian history then we will found king Porus used elephants against the Alexander in battle of hydaspas. Chandragupta maurya did used elephants in his conquest of whole India. Elephants were part of Ashoka's army. ",
            "keyString": "779826s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When Alexander invaded India, Magadha was being ruled by the",
            "optionA": "  Haryankas ",
            "optionB": "  Sisunagas ",
            "optionC": "  Nandas ",
            "optionD": "  Mauryas ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAt the time when Alexander had come to invade India, the most powerful kingdom was Magadha, under the rule of Nanda dynasty. This king maintained a huge force of 200,000 infantry, 80,000 cavalry, 8000 chariots and 6000 war elephants. ",
            "keyString": "779993s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which ruler murdered his father, Bimbisara\nto ascend the throne?",
            "optionA": "  Ashoka ",
            "optionB": "  Ajatshatru ",
            "optionC": "  Kanishka ",
            "optionD": "  Simukha ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tBimbisara was the first ruler of Haryanka dynasty of the Magadha (Capital Rajgriha). His son Ajatshatru imprisoned him and killed him to ascend the throne. ",
            "keyString": "780155s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Nalanda Mahavihara site is in",
            "optionA": "  Rajasthan ",
            "optionB": "  Assam ",
            "optionC": "  Bihar ",
            "optionD": "  Gujrat ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNalanda was a Mahavihara, a large Buddhist monastery, in the ancient kingdom of Magadha (modern-day Bihar) in India. ",
            "keyString": "780328s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which one of the following scholar, challenged Invincible Yajnavalkya for debate?",
            "optionA": "  Ghosha ",
            "optionB": "  Apala ",
            "optionC": "  Maitreyi ",
            "optionD": "  Gargi ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tGargi, as one of the disputants in the debate, questioned Yajnavalkya on his claim of superiority among the scholars. She held repeated arguments with him. Gargi and Yajnavalkya's exchange centered on the ultimate \"warp\" of reality (\"warp\" means \"the basic foundation or material of a structure or entity). Her initial dialogue with Yajnavalkya tended to be too metaphysical, such as unending status of the soul, away from practical situations. She then changed her approach and asked him pointed questions related to the environment existing in the world, the question of the very origin of all existence. ",
            "keyString": "855783s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Alexander and the army of Porus camped on the opposite bank of which river?",
            "optionA": "  Ravi ",
            "optionB": "  Jhelum ",
            "optionC": "  Sutlej ",
            "optionD": "  Chenab ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Battle of the Hydaspes was fought in 326 BC between Alexander the Great and King Porus of the Paurava kingdom on the banks of the river Jhelum (known to the Greeks as Hydaspes) in the Punjab region of the Indian subcontinent (modern-day Punjab, Pakistan). ",
            "keyString": "856262s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "King Kharavela was the greatest ruler of the Chedi Dynasty of",
            "optionA": "  Cholamandalam ",
            "optionB": "  Kalinga ",
            "optionC": "  Kannauj ",
            "optionD": "  Purushpur ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tKharavela was a king of Kalinga in present-day Odisha, India. He ruled somewhere around first or second century BCE. His name is also transliterated as Kharabe\u1e37a. ",
            "keyString": "856805s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The last great ruling dynasty of Magadha was",
            "optionA": "  Sunga ",
            "optionB": "  Kanva ",
            "optionC": "  Kusana ",
            "optionD": "  Gupta ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Gupta Empire was an ancient Indian empire existing from the mid-to-late 3rd century CE to 590 CE. The ruling dynasty of the empire was founded by the king Sri Gupta; the most notable rulers of the dynasty. ",
            "keyString": "858108s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following ruler was responsible for the rise of Magadha?",
            "optionA": "  Bindusara ",
            "optionB": "  Ajatshatru ",
            "optionC": "  Bimbisara ",
            "optionD": "  Vasudeva ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tBimbisara, (born c. 543\u2014died 491 bce), one of the early kings of the Indian kingdom of Magadha. Bimbisara built the city of Rajagriha, famous in Buddhist writings. He was succeeded on the throne by his son Ajatashatru, who murdered his father to obtain power. ",
            "keyString": "858710s27m26h11d13m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        }
    ]
}